There are two ways to pick up the accent, all at once or step by step. There's the
do it now people and the people who like to change slowly thinking that there's no
validity to things that happen quickly to them. People don't think it's real if it's
fast but that's the Nike slogan, just do it. You know you can and even if it's
faster than you expect it's still valid. It's all about behavior modeling. You
don't have to believe it, you just have to do it. All at once. Just do it. Listen to
the sounds and rhythms, capture some essential elements, and go. Step by step.
Apply each technique one by one to develop your voice quality, pronunciation,
intonation, phrasing, and linking. After you've mastered each of these elements,
work on integrating them into speech. Which method will work best for you? We'll
try the all-at-once way first to see if we can jump-start you with this shortcut.
This isn't so much about the American accent as much as it's about you doing
pure mimicry. Don't think. Don't overanalyze. Just imitate exactly what you
hear in every aspect. Voice quality, pronunciation, rhythm, phrasing, and word
flow.